Okay, it's time to build the
stereotypical um to-do list, and that's
so that I can show you a couple of
different ways of editing HTML. Um,
so the first one that I'm going to show
you, um, for that to work, I'm going to
change this P tag to be UL. So, what we
want to do is we would like to take user
input from the input box and add it into
this unordered list of to-do items. So
we've created a fun we said we were
going to call our function create to-do.
So let's make that function function
create todo
and okay well what do we want to do? The
first thing we need to do is we need to
take this item and we need to add it to
the output. So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to uh gather the input. So I'm
going to say let user input equal um
document.getelement
by ID. The ID I want is new item.
And I'm going to grab the value.
And then before I forget, I'm going to
clear the value.
So I'm going to set it equal to nothing.
Um, and then the last thing I want to do
is I want to take this user input and I
want to put it into this ul element.
Well, in order to do that, I have to
access the ul element. So I'm going to
say document.getelement
by id and I'm going to get the output
element
and then I'm going to set its inner
html.
So inner HTML refers to the this portion
right here that line 58 that appears
between the closing tag and the opening
tag. So anything that's in between the
two tags is inner HTML. So, what I'm
doing is I'm saying take the inner the
HTML that's already there. Right now,
there's nothing. And add on some HTML.
And I'm going to use a template string
here and I'm going to say put in a list
item
with the user input
inside of it.
So, what I'm saying is
gather input from the input box.
um reset the input box to nothing and
set the inner HTML. So, I'm going to
come over to my running website and I'm
going to type cell death sticks and add
the to-do and then I'm going to type uh
go home
and then rethink my life.
Okay, so these all successfully added
and in fact if we open up this ul we can
see that there are three list items
here. Cell death sticks go home rethink
my life. The reason this is dangerous is
someone could come here and type button
on click equals alert one.
Hi. And then I'm going to close out that
button.
And because we're directly taking what's
in the input box and putting it on the
page, when I click this, a button has
now been added to the page. And when I
click it, it runs the JavaScript that
was part of that button. So, in other
words, we've opened up our website to
allow just anyone who wants to to come
in, type their own JavaScript, and have
it run on our website, which is really
dangerous. We call these cross-sight
scripting attacks. Um, and it can be
really, really dangerous. So, I'm going
to show you an alternative that you
could consider using. Um, and then in a
few videos, I'll show you another way of
doing this. Um, but the first one is
rather than setting the inner HTML, we
could change this UL to a P tag.
And um, here instead of setting inner
HTML, we can set text content. And what
we'll do is we'll just set it equal to
the user input.
And then let's put a new line. So if we
save this and we come back over, we can
put hi,
hello.
Uh-oh, that put them on the same line.
Well, maybe it's because we used the
JavaScript new line character and we
should have used the break character. So
let's put the break tag in and see what
happens.
I Well, it put the break tag directly
in. That's good news because it means if
they try and do the button trick, um,
it won't put a button.
See, it just put the text. So, that's
not I mean, it it works and our input's
definitely clean, but it would be really
nice if we could have new line items. So
if you want to do that rather than
setting text content, you'll set inner
text and then here you'll put the break
character back. Now we can type our
to-do list. Uh cell death sticks
go home.
And it works like we are expecting.
And so that's the comparison between
inner HTML
text content and inner